Empresses in the Palace—the Legend of Zhen Huan
Adopted from the novel by Liu Lian Zi
[contact translators] carsenwei@yahoo.com
[subtitles subscription] liberapay.com/ZHZSubbers
Theme: Unfortunate Love
Perturbed by the thoughts on my mind
no matter how hard I try to sever my love.
I could give away my crown for the beauty by my side,
but the wheel of fortune turns weals into woes,
and woes into weals.
No one is the master of their own destiny,
the vicissitudes throughout their life.
For the lovers of all time,
who can break the spell of romance?
I could give away my crown for the beauty by my side,
but the wheel of fortune turns weals into woes,
and woes into weals.
No one is the master of their own destiny,
the vicissitudes throughout their life.
For the lovers of all time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Who can break the spell of romance?
[contact translators] carsenwei@yahoo.com
[subtitles subscription] liberapay.com/ZHZSubbers
His Majesty the Emperor.
All rise.
I thank Your Majesty.
What's going on?
I heard that someone defied Your Majesty's decree,
so I came to request a thorough investigation.
Peace to Your Majesty.
What brought you here?
I was chatting with Concubine Estime in the chamber.
Grace and peace to Your Highness.
Why are you here?
Your Highness, where else should I be?
I came to visit Concubine Estime.
We were looking for you, My Lady.
It turns out that you went to Her Highness's.
I have delivered the packages you required
to be sent to Companion Shen, My Lady.
I heard a large procession coming towards Concubine Estime's palace.
I thought that something serious was going on.
Consort Fleur, why did you leave the Cooling Hall and come here instead?
I heard someone trespassed into the Leisured Moon Chamber to visit the confined concubine ...
so I came to investigate.
Do you have a warrant from the Empress?
I came in such a rush ... that I failed to obtain a warrant from the Empress.
When I announced Shen's confinement,
I said that no one shall visit her without my permission.
Did you forget?
Huh?
I...
So did you find the trespasser?
The head maid Orchid refused to let me in.
I haven't seen anyone yet.
Very well!
You are worthy of being my direct servant.
I always obey Your Majesty’s command.
Your majesty, Her Highness always acts decisively.
She must have obtained evidence for her suspicion.
Why don't we search the Leisured Moon Chamber?
For one thing, Her Highness wouldn't have made the trip in vain;
for another, we could bring a conclusion to this incident.
What does Your Majesty think?
Companion Shen is serving her confinement.
I can't bear to see her carry
another accusation of disrespecting Your Majesty.
I hope Your Majesty will send someone into the Leisured Moon Chamber for investigation.
This will prove Companion Shen's innocence.
Although Companion Shen is confined,
we cannot wrongly accuse her.
- Su Peisheng.
- Your Majesty.
- Take a few people to go inside.
- Yes.
Your Lordship, there are only these small boats to travel around on lake.
I will take Your Lordship to the island.
Why are there so many lotus lanterns on the lake?
Yesterday was the Ghost Festival.
We put down the lanterns to offer our prayers.
How could the lanterns compare to the real lotus flowers?
At this time of the year, most lotus flowers have withered.
That's why I need to see the lotus flowers while I still can.
- Err...
- You can go now. I'll row the boat over.
My Lordship, if His Majesty found out, he would
blame us for not taking good care of you.
His Majesty knows me as a brother.
Don't worry. You can go back to work now.
A-Jin, you will go back, too.
Your Majesty,
there was no one else other than Companion Shen and a few servants.
I was terribly concerned upon hearing the news.
I realize I was mistaken.
I do beg Your Majesty's pardon.
I'm aware ...
of the never-ending gossips and rivalries in the harem.
You have long been assisting in the palace affairs.
You should have a sense of priority.
It was my oversight.
I beg for Your Majesty's forgiveness.
I thought you have changed after a period of self-reflection.
But instead, your temper got even worse.
I was hoping to resume your authority in palace management
but it seems that there is no need at all.
Go back to your palace and reflect upon yourself.
Stop causing so much trouble.
I thank Your Majesty.
You are no longer allowed to see Princess Wenyi.
You would only be a bad influence on her.
Your Majesty, I wish to offer a word to Your Majesty.
Yes.
In my view, Companion Shen has been
conducting herself well in her continued confinement.
I wonder if it would be reasonable to dismiss half of the guards?
For one thing, it is an unnecessary overhead in the palace;
For another, it more or less causes
inconvenience and unease to the concubines.
All right.
Please take care of her as she is in your palace.
I'm honored to obey, Your Majesty.
Allow me to take my leave.
I'm glad you were not implicated.
I will not put myself in jeopardy,
or ever disobey Your Majesty's orders.
His Majesty is leaving.
I bid Your Majesty goodbye.
I was too careless and fell into your trap!
Only Your Highness could tell
whether it was because of carelessness.
You set this up against me.
I regret not taking you down earlier.
Your Highness must be joking.
We all serve His Majesty as a family.
His Majesty would be angry should he catch wind of this.
You can be pleased with yourself as a newly favored concubine.
Unfortunately, I do not tolerate any
tricksters like you under my throne.
It is a matter of tolerance whether Your Highness accepts me.
But it's a matter of skill to make Your Highness accept me.
We have a long way to go.
We will wait and see.
Let's go.
By His Majesty's decree, the guards for
the Leisured Moon Chamber will be halved.
- Your team can go back now.
- Yes.
Lady Sourire rewarded you money to treat yourselves to some tea.
What about us?
Don't worry.
Her Highness Concubine Estime appreciates your
hard work and has prepared tea and snacks for you.
We are grateful to Her Highness.
However we are on duty right now.
We should not be eating.
That's not a problem.
All your hard work has not gone unnoticed by Her Highness.
As long as you fulfill your duties, Her Highness will
speak fondly of you all to His Majesty.
Thanks, Madam.
If so, we must not decline Her Highness.
- All right, I will go with you.
- Certainly.
There will be rewards afterwards.
Yes. Follow me.
My Lady, your presumption is correct.
Jade sneaked out from the back door to
Noble Lady Cao's palace not long after you left.
My Lady ...
Should I detain her?
Act as if nothing happened.
Yes, My Lady.
You can go now.
I will interrogate her myself.
Yes.
I have moored the boat in the lotus leaves.
You won't be noticed on the way back, My Lady.
Allow me to take my leave.
Please help me get changed.
That bitch!
She deceived me with Zhen Huan!
Your Highness must not be angry for the good of your health.
They have obviously colluded to claim false allegiance to me.
They have ... It was my oversight.
I was fooled when Jade put on her puppy face.
Well, you would always exercise prudence in your decisions.
How uncommon it was for you to inform me in such a haste!
I was only thinking about Your Highness.
I thought we must eliminate Lady Sourire in time
for her disrespect to Your Highness.
(sneer) Thank you for your concern.
Your Highness ...
May peace restore in your mind
as you enjoy the smell of the Pleasancy.
His Majesty was angry because he cares so much about you.
I'm afraid His Majesty sees only the smiles
of the new concubines but tears of the old ones.
Madam.
The guards are changing shifts right now.
After half of the guards were dismissed,
the remainder are slacking.
Some sedatives were added to their tea.
They must be feeling drowsy now.
The door is unlocked.
I will walk you in, My Lady.
You may leave. Be careful not to attract attention.
Yes.
Meizhuang.
Your hands are so cold.
Don't worry, I'm all right.
Madam Orchid would always tell me you had been very well.
I always had some doubts.
I'm reassured now seeing you here.
Nothing went wrong with me.
But I would always worry about you.
My Ladies, I would stay outside and look out for you.
Please don't take too long.
This is no longer the Leisured Moon Chamber it used to be.
But you are still a concubine.
These ... these servants should be ashamed of themselves.
Consort Fleur is in her prime.
All the servants “turn the helm according to the wind”.
They've been trampling on me.
I could hardly survive to today without Madam Orchid's discreet help.
Even the servants are no longer using such candles.
It burns with so much smoke.
It's all right. It's dark enough in my heart.
It would fall into complete darkness if I don't see any light.
Meizhuang, I assure you I will ask His Majesty
to end your confinement as soon as possible.
Madam Orchid told me you were not implicated in this incident.
That brings peace to my mind.
Fortunately, Lingrong is here with you.
So you won't be too isolated.
By the way, is His Majesty very fond of Lingrong?
Yes.
Even though Lingrong is here, you will still have to
make your own decisions if anything goes wrong.
I'm all right. I'm just worried about you.
You must take the best care of yourself.
Did you hear what was going on outside?
I finally got to take it out on her.
I did.
Although ... she is not that easy to tackle.
Thankfully, His Majesty believes me.
What happened exactly with your pregnancy?
They all said I was feigning a pregnancy for favor.
Even you would not trust me?
With the favor I had at that time,
pregnancy was just a matter of time.
Why did I need to feign a pregnancy?
They deliberately made you think you were pregnant
and testified against you saying you were trying to gain His Majesty's favor.
I'm afraid that from the prescription by Dr. Jiang
to the appointment of Liu Ben ...
it was all part of a plan.
They played on my desire for pregnancy and
set the trap that I would willingly walk into.
It was on me ...
It was all my fault.
It was not until Poria took out the blood-stained underwear
that I realized I wasn't pregnant at all.
His Majesty had intended to resume Consort Fleur's power in harem management.
If I had not set this up against her today, Lingrong and I
would soon have our lives hanging by a thread
I'm already of no use.
It would be great if you can get me released.
Otherwise, your priority is to take care of yourself.
You can never be too cautious.
You must never fall into a plight like this.
Meizhuang, you must not worry.
His Majesty ... His Majesty ...
He would always show grace to you.
Grace?
When we were young in our maiden years,
all we wished for was an adequate husband.
Even though I know equal respect and caring is a luxury
for marriage into the imperial family,
I would always hope to rely on my husband
who can trust and care for me.
It seems that I was wrong after all.
I have told our families to use their best efforts to hunt Liu Ben down.
His Majesty will surely vindicate and compensate you when the truth emerges.
Compensate?
How can he possibly compensate for all my suffering?
One day I was dearly cherished and the next I was abandoned with distrust.
His Majesty ...
What a fickle heart he has!
I thought he would be affectionate about the past.
I know it is harsh for you to hear me saying this.
Without my own plight I wouldn't understand
what His Majesty's affection is.
However, His Majesty treats you exceptionally well.
I didn't think you would have to go through this.
These are just heartbroken words from a heartbroken person.
My Lady, please come out soon.
They will be back soon.
Meizhuang ...
You must take care of your health.
I will do whatever it takes to get you out of here.
My Lady, please come out as fast as you can.
Yes.
My Lady, please come out quickly.
You must take care.
Please go.
Goodbye.
Madam, please take care of her.
Please help her if anything.
My Lady, please be assured.
Peace will remain for a while after today's farce.
Lady Meizhuang will be better off.
My Lady, please go back quickly.
Who's there?
Who is on the boat?
Who is it?
Who is it to disturb my good sleep?
I didn't know Your Lordship is here.
Please forgive me for the offence.
Go. Don't disturb my night.
May I ask why Your Lordship is here?
His Majesty asked me to stay in the palace tonight.
Do you need to question His Majesty?
No, Your Lordship.
It's all right now.
How about I take you back in the boat?
It'll be faster and more convenient.
I thank Your Lordship.
I only heard of the the wind on the lake bringing the fragrance of lotus across ten miles.
Now that I'm on the lake,
I can even smell the pleasant scents of water caltrops and reeds.
Sure enough, one can enjoy much more through immersion than observation.
Not even many lotus pods are left at this time.
[Lotus withers after bearing seeds in late summer.]
I wonder how Your Lordship collected so many lotus flowers?
This is the last harvest for the summer.
I rowed deep into the lotus field and that was all I could collect.
Your Lordship is fond of lotus?
I thought men would prefer pine and bamboo.
Pine and bamboo are stiff and susceptible to fracture.
By comparison, the lotus surfaces untainted from the mud.
While lotus is praised for its purity,
I like it more for its Buddha-like nature.
As gentle as a loving mother.
I agree, My Lady.
I seem to have smelled pollia?
But it shouldn’t be in this season.
You have a sensitive sense of smell, My Lady.
It is my sachet.
Pollia is a symbol of love.
Does Your Lordship have someone in your heart?
It is a real pleasure to be in a boat with a beauty.
It makes me feel as if I was boating on Lake Tai with
Xi Shi [one of the ancient Four Beauties].
Your Lordship, I would be angry if I
didn't know you intended it to be a compliment.
Please do not compare me to Xishi.
Why? Do you also think Xi Shi caused the fall of the Kingdom of Wu?
If you say Xi Shi is the cause of Wu's downfall,
who should be the culprit for the collapse of the Kingdom of Yue?
Lady Sourire is a sensible person.
Why would you say that?
Fan Li was Xi Shi’s lover.
But he sent Xi Shi to be a concubine of the King of Wu.
What a heartless man!
When Xi Shi harbored no grudge
and went boating with him on Lake Tai,
I believe she no longer felt affectionate as before.
People either sympathize with Xi Shi or blame the King of Wu.
But they never criticize Fan Li.
My Lady, I feel inferior to your unique perspective.
The moonlight glazes silver on the lake.
What a beautiful scene for a memorable time!
"What a beautiful scene for a memorable time ...
to the dullness of my garden and my mind."
Your Lordship has also read The Peony Pavilion?
My favorite line is
"Love springs from an unknown origin
and courses deep to an infinite end. "
"It empowers the alive to die,
and revives the dead to life."
Love ...
It has an unseekable source.
Love goes from an unknown start to an unforeseeable end.
Your Lordship will be fortunate to find someone
you deeply and infinitely love.
Being with His Majesty from dawn to dusk,
I wish we will have this type of love.
Your Lordship dropped this.
Thanks.
This sachet is precious to me.
It would be a great regret if I lost it.
It's just a sachet.
Your Lordship can't be serious.
Since it is precious to Your Lordship,
please don’t show it to anyone else.
It might cause unnecessary trouble.
May I ask Your Lordship a favor?
Yes, My Lady.
On the night of Qixi,
I was plunged into trouble but fortunately
Consort Honnête helped me out.
Hence no matter what Your Lordship has heard about that night,
please don’t mention that we met.
Same with tonight.
I will be immensely grateful if Your Lordship agrees.
I won’t tell anyone else.
It was my pleasure to speak freely with you, My Lady.
If I had the honor, I should invite you
to my Cooling Terrace one day
to talk more about history and literature.
The summer has just passed.
The Cooling Terrace might be a bit too chilly for now.
I should not bring Your Lordship more trouble.
Goodbye.
My Lady, you've finally come back!
Jade, pour some water for me.
Did everything go well, My Lady?
I was very worried about you when you were out for so long.
What were you worrying about?
Your safety, My Lady.
I was fine ...
but Consort Fleur wasn't.
She was scolded by His Majesty
and prohibited from seeing Princess Wenyi again.
His Majesty was considering to reinstate
her authority in palace management.
But now, she seems to be in a precarious position.
His Majesty scolded Her Highness?
Yes.
She "wasted a handful of rice
when she failed to steal the chicken".
You reap what you sow.
Am I right, Jade?
Absolutely, My Lady.
Jade, lately you have been exhausted physically and mentally.
I recognize your hard work.
My Lady, I don't deserve you saying that.
When Lady Cao tried to drive a wedge between
His Majesty and me in the Governance Hall,
I suspected that it was someone close to me who leaked the story.
Today when I had barely stepped out of
the Verdant Reading Hall,
this keen messenger absented herself immediately.
Now tell me,
how did Consort Fleur know
I was going to the Leisured Moon Chamber?
I am not the only person who knows
you were going to visit Meizhuang.
My Lady, how could you tell that I was the messenger?
You did act cautiously
but you neglected one thing.
What is it?
The tributary Emerald Honey was an exclusive gift from His Majesty
and I gave all of it to Lady Cao.
I saw her keeping it in her inner chamber.
If you say you were never disloyal to me,
how could you enter her inner chamber?
How could you be scented with the Emerald Honey?
I... I didn't.
If your mouth says no,
use your nose to smell the Emerald Honey on yourself.
It takes days for the smell to fade
despite its subtleness.
Now, will you tell me the truth?
My Lady.
But I have to thank you.
Without your help, how could I have led her into this?
Consort Fleur must be infuriated to the bone with you.
She would probably think we set this up together.
It's not the first time I had "a servant to two masters".
I just never thought that I would fall victim
to my own sister.
You knew it?
Yes, for a long time.
Father told me before we moved into the palace.
It hurts so much more knowing that you are my sister.
Father... What did father say?
He was sorry for everything he put you through.
and asked me to treat you well.
That is why I took you to the palace with me.
I have been looking for a decent family for you
to be married as a primary wife.
If you stayed home,
you would marry a servant at most in the future.
That will encumber you for the rest of your life.
My Lady ...
I am not your master.
I am your elder sister.
I know you are not reconciled to being a maid.
Your name is not included in the pedigree book.
Your name doesn't have the character 玉(yu) like my sister Yurao.
Even your mother's memorial tablet
cannot be enshrined in the ancestral hall.
But Jade, father always has your welfare at heart.
So do I as your elder sister.
No matter how well you treated me,
we are in an aggressively competitive harem.
How could I stand out if no one introduces me to His Majesty?
Do you really believe Lady Cao was helping you?
Concubine Beauté and Escort Yu are
good examples of being a cat's paw.
At the very least, even if you had gained favor from His Majesty,
did you ever see "a flower that would not fade" in the harem?
Did you think of the consequences of
your mother's identity being disclosed?
Not only would the Zhen family be implicated,
our father will also be banished to Ningguta
[a remote and cold border town for criminals].
I had no intentions like that!
Nor did I want to compete with you.
Lady Cao said His Majesty liked you so much
that he would not severely penalize you for any mistakes.
He would just confine you for half a month at most.
As for me ...
I would stand a chance to approach His Majesty
because I resemble you a little bit.
How could you trust her nonsense?
I have already been "walking on the tip of their knives"
even if I have done nothing wrong.
If His Majesty was mad at me,
your face would only provoke exasperation.
You would be very lucky to not incur the death penalty.
I... I was indeed possessed by the devil.
Your momentary thought almost shattered the bond of our sisterhood.
Do you know that I feel envious of you sometimes?
My life is destined and I can't escape my fate.
But you still have the chance to choose
someone to love and grow old and gray with.
Although I can't acknowledge you as my sister in the palace,
I am planning to make you father's honorary daughter
[like a goddaughter but not religious]
so that you will be married from the Zhan family.
Your mother's memorial tablet
will be placed in the family ancestral hall
and your named will be written in the pedigree book.
I hope your wish will be fulfilled.
Huan, I was such a fool.
I didn't know you were so kind and considerate to me.
I made a terrible mistake.
Yurao is still young and we don't have any brothers in the family.
We have to rely on each other.
If we get turned against each other by our enemy,
there would be no hope for our family.
I didn't live up to your expectations.
Please forgive me.
You didn't tell Consort Fleur about your mother, did you?
I only wanted to use a chance to attract His Majesty's attention.
I had no intention to soil the name of our family.
I didn't dare to tell them about such an important thing.
It's fortunate that you didn't.
Consort Fleur will hold a grudge against you from now.
You have to be more than careful in days to come.
I will never stop regretting the mistake I made.
Please don't worry about me.
It's cold at night already.
There aren't any mosquitos now.
We will soon return to the palace for the Mid-Autumn Festival.
My Lady ...
You look worried, My Lady.
I find that His Majesty holds great respect for Concubine Estime.
Concubine Estime shows high virtue and gentle modesty.
His Majesty doesn't ... have much affection for her.
It's at most courtesy and respect.
In the palace, many people hide their light under a bushel.
If she was no one to His Majesty, how could she have
lived all these years peacefully under Consort Fleur?
I think Lady Cao is more suspicious in this incident.
If you think about it, My Lady,
although Consort Fleur is impetuous,
Lady Cao is a very cautious person.
When Jade reported to her,
how did she make Consort Fleur arrive so promptly?
Did she not deliberate over the decision?
Or did she completely believe Jade?
Could it be that she instigated Consort Fleur to go?
If Cao Qinmo didn't use the cassava starch against me,
it must be Consort Fleur.
Doing this to Cao Qinmo's only child ...
might have caused a rift between them.
I don't think that's impossible.
If so, the game is more complicated than we thought.
Please add more honey.
My Lady doesn't like it too sour.
Xiao-Xiazi said that
Noble Prince Guo stopped visiting His Majesty
and traveled to Central Sichuan.
What does it matter to us?
A Noble Prince could go wherever he wants.
Unlike us, all we can see is the square-shaped sky when we look up.
Stop whining.
You'd be complaining about having too many
places to go once you get married.
Look at you!
Are you thinking about getting married?
Stop it!
Or I'm gonna rip your mouth!
Precious Buddha! Why are you so mad?
You would care so much about whether Noble Prince Guo visits ...
How about marrying him?
Are you out of your mind?
I'll stop talking to you if you continue this nonsense.
Aiya, my good sister!
Take it as a joke!
Anyways, if it happens for you and His Lordship,
it's never too late to thank me.
Stop it! Nonsense!
Stop running!
What? Look at you all worried!
I said stop!
Your Majesty, the Empress is still in the bath.
Your Majesty should sleep if you feel tired.
I am reading Su Shi's poems.
"The ten years since death parted us
never seemed to have an end in sight."
"I resist thinking of you but I cannot forget."
What a poem! It drills every word into my heart.
Your Majesty, I don't understand poetry.
Neither does the Empress, I'm afraid.
If only Lady Sourire was here to talk with me!
Here, I need you to send this to the Palace of Pearl Jade.
Yes, Your Majesty.
My Lady, Mr. Su is here.
My Lady, I hope you may forgive me disturbing.
Is there something urgent, sir?
His Majesty ordered me to deliver this to you, My Lady.
His Majesty wishes you sweet dreams, My Lady.
[For Sourire's personal inspection]
"The paired knots on our sashes will tie our hearts as we dream."
His Majesty wrote this himself?
Yes.
Please thank His Majesty on my behalf, Mr. Su.
His Majesty is exhausted from the state affairs.
Where is Su Peisheng?
Mr. Su went to the Palace of Pearl Jade with a box.
What's in the box?
It's a lover's knot.
Your Majesty must not be angry.
What is there to be angry about?
Did His Majesty ever visit Consort Fleur
after coming back to the palace?
They saw each other quite often
but she didn't serve His Majesty overnight.
Hello World!
[contact translators] carsenwei@yahoo.com
[subtitles subscription] liberapay.com/ZHZSubbers
Theme: The Lonely Phoenix
[phoenix is the symbol of an empress]
I dimly recall the colorful blooms in every summer.
They are as distant as the autumn moon in the water.
He loved me with a volatile heart.
And before I knew it, we fell apart.
Behind me are the promises and longing.
Before me lie the flute and the zither.
I loved you with my body and soul
But you hurt me from head to toe.
My wish ran athwart
and I ended up a fool of my destiny.
My love was the wind-swept flowers from a tree.
A plum bloomed in winter hoping for a fruitful summer.
But the irresistible winds of destiny destroyed her wish.
You can hear the flapping of a phoenix
but you will never see it.
What you see is the falling leaves from the phoenix tree.
The falling leaves from the phoenix tree.